Bruno Campera

Backend Software Engineer with a passion for highly scalable and maintainable code. Over 6 years of experience in the IT industry, including working with international teams.

brunoc@alunos.utfpr.edu.br Links: in LinkedIn O GitHub EMAIL: Curitiba/PR, Brazil. LOCATION: PHONE NUMBER: \$\infty\$ +55 41 99665 8096

TECHNICAL SKILLS

• Java • Javascript • Dart • RESTful API development Programming:

Frameworks: • Spring Boot • Quarkus • Flutter

Database and ORM: • PostgreSQL • Hibernate • Spring Data JPA • PanacheORM

> Git for version control Tools:

Processes: · Agile methodologies, mainly Scrum

• Fluent in English • Native Brazilian Portuguese Languages:

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER 12/2023 - Current

FS Tech

· Developing RESTful APIs on the backend with Java 17 and Quarkus. · Modelled and implemented a PostgreSQL database schema using SQL. • Employed usage of Hibernate ORM and PanacheORM for database interaction, along with JQPL and Native SQL. • Used Git for version control.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER 09/2021 - 09/2023

Federal Data Processing Service (SERPRO)

• Worked on the development of the Compras.gov.br procurement platform. • Developed RESTful APIs on the back-end using Java 17 and Spring Boot 3. • Modelled and implemented a PostgreSQL database schema using SQL, with artifacts such as triggers and functions. • Interacted with database through Spring Data JPA and Hibernate ORM, along with JPQL. • Contributed to the development of a Single Page Application (SPA) using Angular, HTML, CSS, and Typescript.

EMBEDDED SOFTWARE ENGINEER 02/2021 - 08/2021

Alta Rail Technology

• Worked on the development of an embedded application for railway trains. • Developed modules in C++ for a distributed application. • Used Google's FlatBuffers library for serialization and module intercommunication.

EMBEDDED SOFTWARE ENGINEER 06/2019 - 01/2021

Agres Sistemas Eletrônicos

- Contributed to the development of an embedded application for farm tractors. Conducted interviews and gathered application requirements. • Developed a C++ application using the Qt 5 framework.
- Enhanced the object-oriented architecture by applying SOLID principles. Designed the user interface with OML following the MVC pattern.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER 11/2017 - 06/2019

ExxonMobil BSC Brasil

INTERN 01/2016 - 10/2017

• Contributed to the development of ABAP programs for the SAP ERP platform. • Developed and maintained SAP ABAP reports. • Created editable forms using SAP Smartforms and Adobe's SAP Interactive Forms technologies. • Developed small utility web applications with HTML, CSS and JavaScript.

INTERN 09/2013 - 04/2014

HSBC Bank Brasil

· Responsible for monitoring data processing on the banking mainframe. · Tracked transactions and their statuses on the mainframe. • Contacted third parties about occasional processing errors.

EDUCATION

2023 AGILE SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT specialization

Federal University of Paraná (UFPR), Curitiba-PR

COMPUTER ENGINEERING degree 2017

Federal University of Technology - Paraná (UTFPR), Curitiba-PR

2009 **COMPUTER TECHNICIAN course**

Escola Técnica Estadual de São Paulo (ETESP), São Paulo-SP